# **BIODATA**

### Objective:

I am a goal-driven, passionate, and committed individual with a great blend of quantitative, and analytical skill, including multitasking and interpersonal skill. I am also a Value-Adding Specialist with proficiency in Business Intelligence Analytics, Big Data Optimization, Analytics Project management and a good knowledge of Mathematics.

#### **Personal Details:**

- Name: ADEDEJI ADETORO ESTHER
- Postal address: Block 18, Flat 3, L.S.P.D.C Estate, Ebute-Metta, Oyingbo, Lagos State.
- Date of birth: 20 th March, 1996.
- Gender: Female
- Parents' names: Inspr. Adedeji Babatunde Sunday.
- Religion: Christianity

### **Interpersonal Skills**

Team WorkProblem SolvingEmotional IntelligenceCritical ThinkingTime managementPlanning & OrganizingPresentation SkillsAdaptabilityEffective Communication

#### Tools

Advanced Excel, Power BI, Python, SQL, Tableau, Think-Cell, R, Knime, ARCGIS.

#### PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

### Octave Analytics (Data Scientist Intern)

July, 2020 - Date

Yaba, Lagos State.

- Actively involved in the analysis, visualization and reporting of insights garnered from performing sentiment analysis on BBNAIJA 2020 tweets.
- Conduct analysis and present findings on Church Viewership Trends during COVID'19 pandemic.
- Explore company's dataset and generated fact-based cuum actionable insights using analytical tools.
- Write data analytics project proposals, built Gantt charts and RACI model.
- Data analytics and visualization projects using R, MySQL, Power BI, Tableau, Thinkcell, Knime.

#### Freelance (Virtual Intern)

February, 2020 - March, 2020

- Built a model using Decision Tree to classify Iris dataset.
- Hands-on experience with data cleaning and analysis using Tableau.
- Effective use of NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, pyplot, Sckit Learn, Random, Scipy libraries in python for data visualization and analysis.
- Explored diagnostic and prescriptive analysis with a dataset about "Employee Attrition Rate" using python libraries.

### Thinkpeople LTD (Graduate Trainee)

January, 2019 - April, 2019

Lekki, Lagos.

- Drafted minutes for board meetings, collaborated with the marketing manager to prepare modules for the company's major projects.
- Deployed an office app, "Trello" to organize work schedule for the various departments in the organization. This improved efficiency of employees by 75%.

• 75% in employee efficiency as a result of the office app, "Trello" I deployed for departmental

### **Hiphe Designs (Intern)**

June, 2018 - September, 2018

Magodo Estate, Lagos.

• Initiated analytics tool to make data-driven decisions in the marketing department.

#### Fishfull Thinking Consult (Student Intern)

**January**, 2017 – June, 2017

October, 2013 - October, 2018

Victoria Isaland, Lagos.

- Attended to over 250 clients on a monthly basis and accelerated sales by 20%.
- Assisted in construction, maintenance and repair of over 150 different sized aquariums.
- Constructed, designed and maintained a 12' by 12' by 16' glass tank till the point of sale.
- Collaborated with colleagues and executed other duties as assigned by the manager.
- Assisted in conceptualizing the scaling process of an energy related application.

### EDUCATION, CERTIFICATIONS AND TRAININGS

## UNIVERSITY OF LAGOS, AKOKA, LAGOS STATE, NIGERIA.

(Second Class Upper Division)

**CERTIFICATIONS** 

**B.Sc. Marine Sciences** 

World Quant University June, 2020

Scientific Computing and Python for Data Science

Analytics Academy March, 2020

Google Analytics for Beginners (Score 80%)

Health & Safety Environment Personnel (Intermediate) May, 2016

**TRAININGS** 

Data Analytics Essentials with Excel & Power - Utiva

Data Analytics using Python, MySQL & Power BI - Dataleum

Introduction to Python - Data Science Nigeria

Employability & Entrepreneurship - Ministry of Education (Lagos State)